A Guide to the Andrew Jackson Montague Papers, 1854-1938
Library of Virginia
- II: Correspondence, 1854-1938., Extent: 37 boxes. (Box 2-38)
  - A: General Correspondence, 1854-1938., 28 boxes (Box 2-29)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1932, M. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1932, Montague, Robert Lynch. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1932, N-P. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1932, R-S. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1932, T-U-V. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1932, W. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, A-B. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, C. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, D-E-F. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, G-H. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1933, Immigration and Deportation. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1933, Interparliamentary Union. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1934, Interparliamentary Union. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, J-K. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, L. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, M. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, Montague. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, N-O-P. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1933, Postal Rate Change. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, R-S. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, T-U. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934, W. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1935, A-B. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1935, C-D. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Eastman Bill. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1935, F. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1935, G-H-I. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1935, J-K-L. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Labor Dispute Act. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Ludlow Amendment. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Lynching--Costigan-Wagner Bill. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Ma-Mc. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Me-Mi. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Mo-Mu. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Mapes Bill. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1935, N-O. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Neutrality Act. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1935, National Recovery Act. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Pa-Pl. (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Po-Pu. (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Pension Acts--Veterans. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Ports. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Q. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Ra-Ri. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Ro-Ry. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Railroads. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1935, Railroad Pension Bill. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1935, [Emergency] Railroad Transportation Act. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1935, S. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1935, T. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, [1934-]1935, Townshend Old Age Pension Act. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1935, U. (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1935, W. (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1936, A-B. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1936, C. (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1936, D-E-F. (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1936, G-H-I. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1936, J-K. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1936, La-Le. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1936, Li-Ly. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1936, Ma. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1936, Mc. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1936, Me-Mi. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1936, Mo-My. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1936, Montague. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1936, N-O-P. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1936, R-S. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1936, T-V. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1936, W-Y. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1938, A-Z. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, no date, A-Z. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - B: U.S. Attorney for Western Virginia, 1893-1896., 1 box (Box 29)
    - Enforcement returns, U.S. District Office, 1893-1896 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - C: Attorney General, 1897-1902., 1 box (Box 29)
    - Campaign for Attorney General, 1897, A-F. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Campaign for Attorney General, 1897, G-M. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Campaign for Attorney General, 1897, P-W. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Attorney General, 1899-1902, A-F. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Attorney General, 1899-1902, G-M. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Attorney General, 1899-1902, O-Y. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - D: Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900-1901., 11 boxes (Box 29-39)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, A. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, B. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, C. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, D-E-F. (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, G. (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, H. (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, J-K. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, L. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, M. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, N-O. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, P-Q. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, R. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, S. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, T. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1900, V-W. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, A. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, B. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, C. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, D-E-F. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, G-H. (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, J-K-L. (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, M. (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, N-O-P. (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, R-S. (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, January 1901, T-V-W-Y. (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, A-B. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, C-D. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, E-F-G. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, H-J-K. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, L. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, M. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, N-P-R. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901, S-T. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, February 1901,. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, A. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, B. (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, C. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, D-E. (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, F. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, G-H. (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, J. (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, K-L. (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, M. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, N-O-P-Q. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, R. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, S. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, T-U-V. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, March 1901, W-Y. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, A. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, B. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, C. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, D-E. (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, F. (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, G. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, H. (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, I-J-K. (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, L. (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, M. (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, N-O. (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, P-Q. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, R. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, S. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, T-U-V. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, April 1901, W-Y. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, A. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, B. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, C. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, D. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, E. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, F. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, G. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, H. (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, I. (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, J. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, K. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, L. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, M. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, N-O. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, P-Q. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, R. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, Sa-Sl. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, Sm-Sy. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, T-U-V. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, May 1901, W-Y. (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, A. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, B. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, C. (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, D. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, E. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, F. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, G. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, H. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, I-J. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, K. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, L. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, M. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, N-O. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, P. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, Q-R. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, S. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, T-V. (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, June 1901, W-Y. (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, July 1901, A-B-C. (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, July 1901, D-E-F. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, July 1901, G-H-J-L. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, July 1901, M-N-P. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, July 1901, R-S-T-W-Y. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, A. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, B. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, C-D-E-F. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, G-H. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, I-J-K-L. (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, M-N-O. (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, P-R-S. (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, August 1901, V-W-Y. (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, September 1901, A-B-C-D. (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, September 1901, E-F-G-H. (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, September 1901, J-K-L. (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, September 1901, M-N-P-Q. (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, September 1901, R-S-T-W. (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, October 1901, A-B-C. (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, October 1901, D-E-F-G. (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, October 1901, H-J-K-L. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, October 1901, M-N-O-P. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, October 1901, R-S-T-W. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, November 1901, A-B-C. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, November 1901, D-E-F-G. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, November 1901, H-I-J. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, November 1901, K-L-M. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, November 1901, N-O-P-Q. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, November 1901, R-S-T. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, October 1901, V-W-Y. (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1901, Lists. (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1901, Miscellaneous notes, lists, etc. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - E: Board of Education, 1900-1901., 2 boxes (Box 37-38)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, A-B-C. (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, D-E-F-G. (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, H. (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, I-J-K-L. (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, M-N-P. (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, R-S-T. (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Board of Education, August 1900-March 1901, V-W-Y. (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, A. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, B. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, C-D. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, E-F-G. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, H-I-J. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, L. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, M-N. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, P-Q-R. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, S. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Board of Education, April 1901, T-W. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Board of Education, May-October 1901, B-C-D-E. (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Board of Education, May-October 1901, F-G-H. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Board of Education, May-October 1901, J-K-L. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Board of Education, May-October 1901, M-N-O-P. (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Board of Education, May-October 1901, R-S-T-W. (Box 38, Folder 15)
- III: Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 38-40)
  Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, concerns claims based on military service in various wars and consisting of papers sent to Montague as a Congressman for veterans, widows, and family members.
  Alphabetical
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, B. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, D, F. (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, H. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, K, L. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, M. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Ta. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Te-Th. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, To-Ty. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, U-V. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Wa. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, We. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Wh. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Wi. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Wo. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Wr-Wy. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Y. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Veterans' Claims, 1918-1936, Z. (Box 40, Folder 6)
- IV: Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1926-1935., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 40-41)
  Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1926-1935, contains correspondence, reports, and other materials concerning the endowment and its organization and operation.
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1926-1927. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1928. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, January-March 1929. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, April 1929. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, May-December 1929. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1930. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1935. (Box 41, Folder 3)
- V: Applications and Recommendations, 1934-1936., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 41-42)
  V: Applications and Recommendations, 1934-1936, contains corresopndence between Montague and constituents hoping to find work in the federal government. Also includes correspondence with government officials concerning job-seekers.
  Alphabetical, then chronological
  - Applications and Recommendations, C, 1936. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Applications and Recommendations, K, 1934. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Applications and Recommendations, K, 1935. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Applications and Recommendations, L, 1935. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Ma-Me, 1935. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Mi-Mu, 1935. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Ma, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Me-My, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Applications and Recommendations, N, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Applications and Recommendations, O, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Pa-Pe, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Ph-Py, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Applications and Recommendations, Q, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Applications and Recommendations, R, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Applications and Recommendations, T, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Applications and Recommendations, multiple, 1936. (Box 42, Folder 10)
- VI: Speeches, 1892-1925., Extent: 1 box. (Box 43)
  Speeches, 1892-1925, of Montague including political speeches and speeches to organizations. Includes his speech given when nominated for governor of Virginia and his inaugural address. Includes several speeches concerning the South.
  - Address of A. J. Montague, Esq., Delivered before the Literary Societies of William and Mary College, On 29th June 1892 (2 copies). (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Acceptance speech for the gubernatorial nomination, 14 August 1901, Norfolk, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Speech of Honorable A. J. Montague, 4 June 1901, Old Market Hall, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Inaugural address [typescript], 1 January 1902, Constitutional Convention, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Inaugural address [printed], 1 January 1902, Constitutional Convention, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Speech at the Good Roads Convention, 4 April 1902, Charlottesville, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Speech at the Jefferson Memorial Dinner, 19 April 1903, Washington D.C. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Welcoming address [abstract] to the Southern Education Conference, 23 April 1903, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - The South should not be viewed..., 4 January 1904, New York, New York. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Speech at the Academy of Music, 5 November 1904, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Notes for a campaign speech, [1905]. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Speech, Senatorial Campaign, 1905. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - The South Today,8 March 1907, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Response to the toast The Future of American Republics,23 August 1907, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Toast response The South,, ca. 1907, St. Louis, Missouri. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Speech at Goshen Bryan Club Celebration, 15 October 1908, Goshen, Virginia. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - The South and the Nation,1909, University of Chicago. (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - The Monroe Doctrine,7 July 1915, Indiana State Bar Association, Indianapolis, Indiana. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Speech on President Woodrow Wilson and the peace conference, 14 January 1919, House of Representatives. (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Lexington,19 April 1925, Lexington, Massachusetts. (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Speech on Virginia's public schools to the Co-operative Education Association, ca. 1925. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - The political aspirations of men...,no date. (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Speeches and papers, no date. (Box 43, Folder 23)
- VII: Financial Records, 1890-1938., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 43-44)
  Financial Records, 1889-1938, consisting of bills, receipts, check books, bank statements, stock certificates, and other financial records. Also includes business records, stock certificates, and insurance papers of Joseph W. Blanton.
  - Bills and receipts, 1890-1897. (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Bills and receipts, 1901-1911. (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Bills and receipts, 1914-1930. (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Bills and receipts, 1930-1938. (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Bills and receipts, no date. (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Central National Bank check books and statements. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - District National Bank check books and statements, 1923-1933. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - [State] Planters National Bank checks and statements, 1934-1935. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Riggs National Bank checks and statements, 1928-1933. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Riggs National Bank check book and slips, 1930-1933. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Southern Trust and Commerce Bank statements, 1920. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - West End Bank checks and slips, 1924-1930. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Bank records (miscellaneous), 1894-1898. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Check books (miscellaneous), 1902-1935. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Stock certificates and papers, 1889-1933. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Joseph W. Blanton business records, 1890-1906. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Joseph W. Blanton stock certificates, 1890-1907. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Joseph W. Blanton insurance policies, 1897-1908. (Box 44, Folder 13)
- VIII: Miscellany., Extent: 1 box. (Box 44)
  Miscellany contains campaign buttons and ephemera, certificates, genealogy notes, notes, passports, political papers, professorial papers, recipes, ribbons, schedules, voter lists, and other papers and items.
  - Notes and schedules. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Pittsylvania County, Virginia, voter lists, 1890. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Membership certificate for A. J. Montague from the ACCA Temple-Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Montague for Governor ribbon, 1901. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Campaign button, 1901. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Statement to the Senate of Virginia by J. K. Fulton regarding appointment as superintendant of instruction for Grayson County. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Special passport to A. J. Montague as U.S. Delegate to the 3rd International Conference of American States, 9 June 1906. (Box 45, Folder 7)